<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-20T15:47:04-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title>Shaw Gravitt - Writing. Thinking. Living.</title><subtitle>Shaw Gravitt - writer &amp; web developer
</subtitle><author><name>Shaw Gravitt</name><email>smgravitt@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title>Make Good Art</title><link href="http://localhost:4000//inspiration/neil-gaiman-make-good-art" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Make Good Art" /><published>2019-07-13T08:08:08-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T08:08:08-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//inspiration/neil-gaiman-make-good-art</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000//inspiration/neil-gaiman-make-good-art">&lt;div class=&quot;video-responsive&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe title=&quot;youtubeMakeGoodArt&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ikAb-NYkseI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;If you enjoy his voice as much as I do, listen to some of his audiobooks, you won’t regret it.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2jNec3p&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/a&gt;  gives one of the greatest commencement speeches of all time to the 2012 class at the University of the Arts in Philadelphia. The speech was so good it was adapted into a book: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2jNfECT&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Make Good Art&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many good things to take form this speech but here a few tidbits to get you started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advice for getting through tough times:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When things get tough, this is what you should do: Make good art. I’m serious. Husband runs off with a politician — make good art. Leg crushed and then eaten by a mutated boa constrictor — make good art. IRS on your trail — make good art. Cat exploded — make good art. Someone on the Internet thinks what you’re doing is stupid or evil or it’s all been done before — make good art. Probably things will work out somehow, eventually time will take the sting away, and that doesn’t even matter. Do what only you can do best: Make good art. Make it on the bad days, make it on the good days, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He encourages us to make mistakes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I hope that in this year to come, you make mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Because if you are making mistakes, then you are making new things, trying new things, learning, living, pushing yourself, changing yourself, changing your world. You’re doing things you’ve never done before, and more importantly, you’re Doing Something.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So that’s my wish for you, and all of us, and my wish for myself. Make New Mistakes. Make glorious, amazing mistakes. Make mistakes nobody’s ever made before. Don’t freeze, don’t stop, don’t worry that it isn’t good enough, or it isn’t perfect, whatever it is: art, or love, or work or family or life.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Whatever it is you’re scared of doing, Do it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Make your mistakes, next year and forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Shaw Gravitt</name><email>smgravitt@gmail.com</email></author><summary>If you enjoy his voice as much as I do, listen to some of his audiobooks, you won’t regret it.</summary></entry><entry><title>The Blacksmith</title><link href="http://localhost:4000//stories/the-blacksmith" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Blacksmith" /><published>2019-06-25T05:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-25T05:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//stories/the-blacksmith</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000//stories/the-blacksmith">&lt;p&gt;“Damit Callaway! You make my life a living hell! You know that?” Ox said as he stumbled into my shop drunk, again. I could smell the moonshine on him from ten feet away. “Did you know you make my life hell?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t respond; experience taught me talking to the son of our little enclave’s “mayor” when he was drunk only added fuel to his fire. I turned back to my work and continued on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know, you’re lucky. No one else in our little village has the experience you have,” he said. “But you know what? I think you are full of it. I think you’re a faker. If my daddy hadn’t lost his hands he’d be the one in here workin’, and you’d be out on your ass. I’d kick you out if I could.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wasn’t far off. In another life, the life before this hell, I was a computer engineer. I sat behind a desk all day. My experience in anything close to blacksmithing was a class I took over a couple of weekends at the local tech school. We’d learned the basics of bladesmithing. I’d wanted to start a hobby making my own knives. Something different to do in my spare time, working with my hands, as far from the keyboard as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ox was about six feet tall and maybe weighed 130 pounds. He hunched his shoulders making him a few inches shorter than he should be. And his neck curved forward and up pushing his Adam’s out, causing it to protrude from his throat. Along with a too-big-for-his-face nose, he had a very bird-like appearance. He paced back and forth on the other side of the little counter I had in my shop, separating me and my work from folks who came to visit. There were pieces scattered about. Some were new knives, arrowheads, spikes used for protecting our village. And some were farm tools I’d either mended or crafted for folks in the village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My daddy knows how to do what you do. Part of owning a junkyard I s’pect.” Ox picked up and dropped a dull ax head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our “village” is an old junkyard deep in a valley of the Appalachians some of us managed to escape to when the world went to shit. A good place to escape to in many aspects. We were able to build walls out of stacked cars and school buses. And there is plenty of scrap metal around to melt down and re-purpose for weapons and farm tools. Ox’s father is the owner of the junkyard, which put him in the position to call himself the “mayor.” He’s a fair man; can’t complain about him too much, but his son is a huge pain in everyone’s ass. He does nothing to contribute to the community. More a drunk, entitled “Sheriff of Nottingham type” without any authority except to cry to his father.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know what? I bet I could do this job. I could do it better and faster than you and your stuttering fool back there.” He pointed a half-completed knife blade to the back of my shop where my assistant Jim leaned against the door frame to a small office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a damn miracle the two of you get any work done. He can’t get a damn sentence out in less than five minutes, and you might say a dozen words a month. That’s why you’re so slow, you two can’t communicate.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued to work on a pitchfork, or trident – depending on its intended use – I’d been fixing when Ox walked in. All he wanted was to get a rise out of me, any response. I pretty well blocked him out with the rhythm of my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tink, tink, tink with my hammer on the orange glowing tines and the whirl of a hand-cranked bellows fan. Always aware of Ox, I had to turn my back to him every time I went to the forge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a calm rhythm to the work. I could block out the hell our world had turned to. Block out the memories of the life I used to have, the family I used to have. It gave me a purpose as well, a way to help others. And Ox loved to get good and liquored up on moonshine and try to get me riled up. I may have been the only person around who didn’t cater to him, and it drove him insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim was an easy target for him, a schoolyard bully picking on the kid with a speech impediment. The thing was, Jim was one of the smartest people in our village and could manhandle Ox with ease if the need arose. He’d engineered many of our more complicated projects, and I’d done the metal work–he did the heavy lifting. But over time Jim learned to keep quiet so people wouldn’t make fun of him for his stutter. We’d worked out our own form of silent communication, and it worked well for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is that why you don’t got no family?” Ox said. “‘Cus you never talked to your wife?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tink, tink, whirl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know you hold up this entire community with your slow work. We can’t trade – harvest is slow without ‘nough tools, weak without ‘nough weapons.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tink, tink, whirl, tink, tink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is that what happened? You ignored your wife and she left you? Couldn’t take being ignored all the time?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned back to the forge, spinning the bellows handle, keeping the hammer in my hand in case he came around the counter. I shuffled the coals with the pitchfork, the ends red-hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ox threw the half-finished knife at the wall trying to make it stick, it bounced back almost hitting him in the face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Damnit, Callaway! I swear to God!” He picked up a sickle sitting on the edge of the counter and charged at me, stumbling to get around the corner of my counter. Jim left his perch from the office door to head off Ox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned and wedged the handle of the pitchfork into the side of my anvil, expecting the red-hot tines pointing at him to stop his charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no, he ran straight into the glowing red end of the pitchfork, his skin sizzled as the points pierced into his chest below his sternum, instantly cauterizing the wound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He rolled to the ground, pitchfork and handle sticking straight up like a dinner fork stuck in a piece of steak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim stared at me. Both of us with the same series of thoughts. It was self-defense. I’d done the community a big favor. But I could’ve just knocked him to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well…” I said. “You better run off and get the sheriff.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim continued to look at me in shock, terrified. He looked down at Ox and then back to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Run off. I’ll wait here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I leaned back against the closest workbench, crossed my arms and waited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s all the fuss about Callaway? Jim came running up in a tizzy,” the sheriff said walking into the shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pointed to the ground in front of my feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well damn Callaway,” the sheriff laughed. “Jim, I wish I coulda heard you say ‘Ox finally got what he deserved.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim shrugged. If we didn’t know any better we’d all assume he was mute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This puts me in an awkward situation, Callaway. I want to shake your hand and say ‘thank you,’ but I need to take you to the mayor on this one. Don’t know what he is going to do, with your place in the community and all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is what it is,” I said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It looks to me like self-defense, he’s coming at you with the sickle there. In the old world, this’d be a open, shut case. But it ain’t that no more, is it? Let’s go I guess.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wiped my hands on my work apron and hung it on a hook next to the forge. We stepped out into the cool night and headed up to the mayor’s trailer at the top of the hill. I signaled to Jim to stay behind, leaving him to stay in the tiny shed with a dead body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I got banished from the community at least I could leave knowing I’d left it better than I arrived. If the mayor decided to execute me, I could escape the hell of this world and see my wife and daughter in the next life. I was ready for whatever punishment handed down to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My fate was in the hands of a handless man.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Shaw Gravitt</name><email>smgravitt@gmail.com</email></author><summary>“Damit Callaway! You make my life a living hell! You know that?” Ox said as he stumbled into my shop drunk, again. I could smell the moonshine on him from ten feet away. “Did you know you make my life hell?”</summary></entry><entry><title>Do More</title><link href="http://localhost:4000//inspiration/do-more" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do More" /><published>2019-06-15T08:08:08-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-15T08:08:08-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//inspiration/do-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000//inspiration/do-more">&lt;div class=&quot;video-responsive&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe title=&quot;youtubeDoMore&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VnSMIgsPj5M&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;video not 100% safe for work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fantastic reading by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benedict_Cumberbatch&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Benedict Cumberbatch&lt;/a&gt; of a letter from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sol_LeWitt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Sol LeWitt&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eva_Hesse&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Eva Hesse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get out of your head and just DO your art. This is a great reminder to create more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do more. More nonsensical, more crazy, more machines… make them
abound with nonsense. Try and tickle something inside you, your “weird
humor.” You belong in the most secret part of you. Don’t worry about
cool, make your own uncool. Make your own, your own world. If you
fear, make it work for you — draw &amp;amp; paint your fear &amp;amp; anxiety… You
must practice being stupid, dumb, unthinking, empty. Then you will be
able to&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;do&quot;&gt;DO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime you need to create &lt;em&gt;bad work&lt;/em&gt; to get to the good work or to find what you are really supposed to be working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Try to do some BAD work — the worst you can think of and see what
happens but mainly relax and let everything go to hell — you are not
responsible for the world — you are only responsible for your work —
so DO IT. And don’t think that your work has to conform to any
preconceived form, idea or flavor. It can be anything you want it to
be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Shaw Gravitt</name><email>smgravitt@gmail.com</email></author><summary>video not 100% safe for work</summary></entry><entry><title>Problem, Solved?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000//stories/problem-solved" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Problem, Solved?" /><published>2018-08-15T07:23:36-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-15T07:23:36-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//stories/problem-solved</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000//stories/problem-solved">&lt;p&gt;&quot;I mean, how often do you get an opportunity like this?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I loved, and hated, about Kara, she always did her damndest to fix your problems, even if you had no desire whatsoever to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this about her and is probably why, subconsciously, I told her about my current predicament. In my mind I wanted someone to listen to me complain, to have a sounding board, just to vent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But no, I asked my one friend that can't leave a problem untouched. I could have asked anyone else close to me, and I could have screamed it into the void of a caring face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked Kara. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I barely got the thought out before her mind was working up ways of fixing it, of talking me off the ledge, of convincing me how stupid I was, and to do what she thought was best. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Can we at least wait until our drinks are here before we get into it?&quot; I said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If you wanted to wait, you shouldn't have told me all about it on the walk over here.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She's right. I did spill the beans not five minutes after we met up outside of her apartment. We had texted back and forth for a week to set up drinks after work, and when we finally got together I was about to explode. It didn't help that we walked around midtown for 20 minutes trying to decide which bar we wanted to go to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kara is a bit of a partier. Nothing bad, but she can hold her liquor, and does so two or three nights a week. She had an opinion on every bar we walked by until we got to one that was acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;One Henricks and soda and one Evan Williams and Coke.&quot; The bartender said as he set our drinks down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;How much do you make now? I think you can afford to buy whiskey that sits on a shelf. Evan doesn't even get shelf space,&quot; I said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Don't be hating on my good friend. Evan and I have history together. And when you drink as many of these in a week as I do, you don't want to spend $12 a pop for something that only tastes marginally better.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;How do you not have diabetes drinking so many Cokes?&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Look, I do three things with my week: hunt for young blonde men, workout, go to work. In that order.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;At least you know yourself. Any current young blonde men in your life?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Not at the moment. Stop trying to divert from the issues at hand! You have your drink, so now I get to say my piece.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Kara is aware of a problem, she can't let it rest – and I know her argument, but sometimes you have to hear it to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;OK then. Give it to me.&quot; I said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She took a deep breath, looked me straight in the eye and said: &quot;You're a fucking idiot&quot; and took a long sip of her drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Ouch. I'm glad I waited for the gin. A bit harsh.&quot; I said, taken back but also appreciating it, a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;You do the same shit over and over again. You meet someone, you get all hot and heavy a little too fast, and one of two things happen.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She takes another sip, she's already halfway through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;One, the relationship goes on for way longer than it needs to. You get to the point – like you were with the one from high school – where, by the end of it you're saying it should've been over two years sooner.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;OK, yeah. And two?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Or two, you end up heartbroken and depressed for a few months over someone who wasn't worth your time in the first place. And look, I know I'm not the poster child for relationship advice; I haven't had a serious boyfriend since high school. But this is easy to see from the outside looking in.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She's right. That has been my M.O. in the past, except for maybe one or two in college. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;So what do I do then?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Seriously‽ Are you kidding me‽ You've wanted this or something like it since we were in college. I thought you were crazy for even trying. And now you have the chance to achieve a huge fucking dream, and you are wavering over it?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She finishes off her drink and sets it on the inside of the bar so the bartender can see it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;And to be honest, it fucking pisses me off you even have to stop to think about it. Fuck buddies come and go. And yes, so do jobs, but not jobs like this. Not jobs you have wanted for over a decade, maybe more.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could tell she was starting to feel a buzz. When she gets fired up and has a drink in her, she cusses like a sailor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;One more please.&quot; She says to the bartender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Yeah but this one feels different. What if taking this job ruins it, and it could be something? I don't want to be 50, alone, and only have my career to show for it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;You're still young. There's plenty of time to meet people between now and 50. If it's meant to work, it'll work. If it doesn't work, it saves future &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; the heartache.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;What about leaving you and everyone else behind?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;You aren't dying. You will eventually come back, and you will still communicate with everyone.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take a long sip and finish off my gin and soda. I'll miss Hendricks when I'm gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Right? You'll still communicate with everyone… I know it's not as easy as just texting or calling me up, but it's still a possibility, right?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Well, the texting part will be almost as easy, with a delay. But, it won't be the same as a face to face conversation.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Yeah but how often are you really talking to your family in person? Same with some of our friends. I rarely see some of them at all except for their Insta pics.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;True, most of them I rarely see in person anymore,&quot; I nod to the bartender for another drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;What are you so afraid of?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I don't know. The regular stuff, you know.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;No, I don't know.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baited. It annoys the crap out of me. I'm just giving her ammo to more strongly prove her point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Oh, come on.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Tell me why you're so afraid of something you've been waiting for, working your ass off for. A job that most people would kill for. Hell,&quot; she whispers, &quot;someone may have killed to be in your position.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She stops and dramatically looks over my shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Actually, you should probably watch your back. &lt;i&gt;That&lt;/i&gt;, I guess is a legitimate fear, and I'll give you that one.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;You know, the usual stuff.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;What usual stuff?&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I've wanted this for so long – it's such a big dream – accomplishing it is scary. And failure. What if I get there and can't handle it? What if I wash out and have to quit?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Failure? Really‽ They know it's hard. They wouldn't have recruited you if they didn't think there was a possibility of you making it through.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Yeah, but it's all still scary as hell.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Yeah, well, life can do that sometimes. I'm going to get a little philosophical on your ass.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She takes another long drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Life is scary as shit, but you're the result of a long line of survivors. You wouldn't be here today if someone, in the generations before you, hadn't survived. Thousands and thousands, hell maybe millions of people, have survived for you to be here right now – don't let all that survivor-ing go to waste.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I must be drunk, that sort of makes sense.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Damn right it makes sense. You got here somehow.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;That's true. I get everything you are saying, but I'm still scared shittless of going. I mean, yeah sure I'll likely survive, but it's not any less terrifying. And you know there is a possibility I won't survive.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Maybe what I'm getting at is, you and I, we're survivors. There's courage in us, and courage has spread through the people who've come before us. Courage is contagious. One person in a room starts acting like a little bitch in a horror movie, and you know the bad guy is going to come in and get everyone. But when one person starts talking like a badass, all of a sudden the bad guy is going to have a bad day.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Hmm, okay.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Plus, I need the bragging rights. I need to tell people ‘Hell yeah my best friend is a badass!' I'm going tell every guy in the bar.&quot; She smirks, &quot;At least do it so I can get laid.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Why didn't you lead with that? I'm sold.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Best friends are supposed to help each other get laid.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;You know this is just an invitation to the join the training program. I have to get through everything first.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Well, what the hell are you doing sitting in this bar drinking? Shouldn't you be out there running and doing push-ups or something?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Ha. Probably!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The worst thing that can happen is you get there, you realize it's not for you for whatever reason, and you come back here. We sit at this bar and have a drink, and you tell me all about it. That doesn't sound too terrible to me.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;That's true.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &quot;So that means you're taking it right? Are you going to tell the boo about your decision?&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;In time. It'll work or it won't. I'm not going to let it get in the way of your bragging rights.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content><author><name>Shaw Gravitt</name><email>smgravitt@gmail.com</email></author><summary>&quot;I mean, how often do you get an opportunity like this?&quot;
One thing I loved, and hated, about Kara, she always did her damndest to fix your problems, even if you had no desire whatsoever to fix it.
I know this about her and is probably why, subconsciously, I told her about my current predicament. In my mind I wanted someone to listen to me complain, to have a sounding board, just to vent. 
But no, I asked my one friend that can't leave a problem untouched. I could have asked anyone else close to me, and I could have screamed it into the void of a caring face.
But no.
I asked Kara. 
I barely got the thought out before her mind was working up ways of fixing it, of talking me off the ledge, of convincing me how stupid I was, and to do what she thought was best. 
&quot;Can we at least wait until our drinks are here before we get into it?&quot; I said.
&quot;If you wanted to wait, you shouldn't have told me all about it on the walk over here.&quot;
She's right. I did spill the beans not five minutes after we met up outside of her apartment. We had texted back and forth for a week to set up drinks after work, and when we finally got together I was about to explode. It didn't help that we walked around midtown for 20 minutes trying to decide which bar we wanted to go to. 
Kara is a bit of a partier. Nothing bad, but she can hold her liquor, and does so two or three nights a week. She had an opinion on every bar we walked by until we got to one that was acceptable.
&quot;One Henricks and soda and one Evan Williams and Coke.&quot; The bartender said as he set our drinks down.
&quot;How much do you make now? I think you can afford to buy whiskey that sits on a shelf. Evan doesn't even get shelf space,&quot; I said. 
&quot;Don't be hating on my good friend. Evan and I have history together. And when you drink as many of these in a week as I do, you don't want to spend $12 a pop for something that only tastes marginally better.&quot;
&quot;How do you not have diabetes drinking so many Cokes?&quot; 
&quot;Look, I do three things with my week: hunt for young blonde men, workout, go to work. In that order.&quot;
&quot;At least you know yourself. Any current young blonde men in your life?&quot;
&quot;Not at the moment. Stop trying to divert from the issues at hand! You have your drink, so now I get to say my piece.&quot;
When Kara is aware of a problem, she can't let it rest – and I know her argument, but sometimes you have to hear it to understand it.
&quot;OK then. Give it to me.&quot; I said.
She took a deep breath, looked me straight in the eye and said: &quot;You're a fucking idiot&quot; and took a long sip of her drink.
&quot;Ouch. I'm glad I waited for the gin. A bit harsh.&quot; I said, taken back but also appreciating it, a bit.
&quot;You do the same shit over and over again. You meet someone, you get all hot and heavy a little too fast, and one of two things happen.&quot;
She takes another sip, she's already halfway through.
&quot;One, the relationship goes on for way longer than it needs to. You get to the point – like you were with the one from high school – where, by the end of it you're saying it should've been over two years sooner.&quot;
&quot;OK, yeah. And two?&quot;
&quot;Or two, you end up heartbroken and depressed for a few months over someone who wasn't worth your time in the first place. And look, I know I'm not the poster child for relationship advice; I haven't had a serious boyfriend since high school. But this is easy to see from the outside looking in.&quot;
She's right. That has been my M.O. in the past, except for maybe one or two in college. 
&quot;So what do I do then?&quot;
&quot;Seriously‽ Are you kidding me‽ You've wanted this or something like it since we were in college. I thought you were crazy for even trying. And now you have the chance to achieve a huge fucking dream, and you are wavering over it?&quot;
She finishes off her drink and sets it on the inside of the bar so the bartender can see it. 
&quot;And to be honest, it fucking pisses me off you even have to stop to think about it. Fuck buddies come and go. And yes, so do jobs, but not jobs like this. Not jobs you have wanted for over a decade, maybe more.&quot;
I could tell she was starting to feel a buzz. When she gets fired up and has a drink in her, she cusses like a sailor. 
&quot;One more please.&quot; She says to the bartender.
&quot;Yeah but this one feels different. What if taking this job ruins it, and it could be something? I don't want to be 50, alone, and only have my career to show for it.&quot;
&quot;You're still young. There's plenty of time to meet people between now and 50. If it's meant to work, it'll work. If it doesn't work, it saves future you the heartache.&quot;
&quot;What about leaving you and everyone else behind?&quot;
&quot;You aren't dying. You will eventually come back, and you will still communicate with everyone.&quot;
I take a long sip and finish off my gin and soda. I'll miss Hendricks when I'm gone.
&quot;Right? You'll still communicate with everyone… I know it's not as easy as just texting or calling me up, but it's still a possibility, right?&quot;
&quot;Well, the texting part will be almost as easy, with a delay. But, it won't be the same as a face to face conversation.&quot; 
&quot;Yeah but how often are you really talking to your family in person? Same with some of our friends. I rarely see some of them at all except for their Insta pics.&quot;
&quot;True, most of them I rarely see in person anymore,&quot; I nod to the bartender for another drink.
&quot;What are you so afraid of?&quot;
&quot;I don't know. The regular stuff, you know.&quot;
&quot;No, I don't know.&quot;
Baited. It annoys the crap out of me. I'm just giving her ammo to more strongly prove her point. 
&quot;Oh, come on.&quot;
&quot;Tell me why you're so afraid of something you've been waiting for, working your ass off for. A job that most people would kill for. Hell,&quot; she whispers, &quot;someone may have killed to be in your position.&quot;
She stops and dramatically looks over my shoulder.
&quot;Actually, you should probably watch your back. That, I guess is a legitimate fear, and I'll give you that one.&quot;
&quot;You know, the usual stuff.&quot;
&quot;What usual stuff?&quot; 
&quot;I've wanted this for so long – it's such a big dream – accomplishing it is scary. And failure. What if I get there and can't handle it? What if I wash out and have to quit?&quot;
&quot;Failure? Really‽ They know it's hard. They wouldn't have recruited you if they didn't think there was a possibility of you making it through.&quot;
&quot;Yeah, but it's all still scary as hell.&quot;
&quot;Yeah, well, life can do that sometimes. I'm going to get a little philosophical on your ass.&quot; 
She takes another long drink.
&quot;Life is scary as shit, but you're the result of a long line of survivors. You wouldn't be here today if someone, in the generations before you, hadn't survived. Thousands and thousands, hell maybe millions of people, have survived for you to be here right now – don't let all that survivor-ing go to waste.&quot;
&quot;I must be drunk, that sort of makes sense.&quot;
&quot;Damn right it makes sense. You got here somehow.&quot;
&quot;That's true. I get everything you are saying, but I'm still scared shittless of going. I mean, yeah sure I'll likely survive, but it's not any less terrifying. And you know there is a possibility I won't survive.&quot;
&quot;Maybe what I'm getting at is, you and I, we're survivors. There's courage in us, and courage has spread through the people who've come before us. Courage is contagious. One person in a room starts acting like a little bitch in a horror movie, and you know the bad guy is going to come in and get everyone. But when one person starts talking like a badass, all of a sudden the bad guy is going to have a bad day.&quot;
&quot;Hmm, okay.&quot;
&quot;Plus, I need the bragging rights. I need to tell people ‘Hell yeah my best friend is a badass!' I'm going tell every guy in the bar.&quot; She smirks, &quot;At least do it so I can get laid.&quot;
&quot;Why didn't you lead with that? I'm sold.&quot;
&quot;Best friends are supposed to help each other get laid.&quot;
&quot;You know this is just an invitation to the join the training program. I have to get through everything first.&quot;
&quot;Well, what the hell are you doing sitting in this bar drinking? Shouldn't you be out there running and doing push-ups or something?&quot;
&quot;Ha. Probably!&quot;
&quot;The worst thing that can happen is you get there, you realize it's not for you for whatever reason, and you come back here. We sit at this bar and have a drink, and you tell me all about it. That doesn't sound too terrible to me.&quot;
&quot;That's true.&quot;
 &quot;So that means you're taking it right? Are you going to tell the boo about your decision?&quot; 
&quot;In time. It'll work or it won't. I'm not going to let it get in the way of your bragging rights.&quot;</summary></entry><entry><title>Fancy Dinners For My Wife, God Bless her</title><link href="http://localhost:4000//stories/fancy-dinners-for-my-wife-god-bless-her" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fancy Dinners For My Wife, God Bless her" /><published>2018-07-22T07:23:36-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-22T07:23:36-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//stories/fancy-dinners-for-my-wife-god-bless-her</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000//stories/fancy-dinners-for-my-wife-god-bless-her">&lt;p&gt;There is a shit ton, pardon ma french, of money to be made as a landfill miner, but I ‘spect ya already know that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out as a heavy equipment operator, ma job was to make sure all the garbage dumped was packed down good'n'tight and then bury it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a good job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first 5 or 6 years I kept ma mind occupied by smokin' cigarettes. I'd just smoke one after the other and push the trash around, bury it, keep the dump goin'. It was good honest work, ya got over the smell eventually and we got insurance outta it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But anyway, I'd drive ma dozer around and smoke like a chimney all day ‘til ma wife, God Bless her, told me I had to quit. I told her smokin' weren't any worse than the trash air I was breathin' all day long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She weren't havin' none of it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to quit smokin'. So I did. It weren't easy and it took me a good while, I mean hell, what was I supposed to do all day with ma wanderin' mind, sittin' in the cab of ma dozer all by maself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ya know what helped me quit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That damn first iPhone I found. That thing changed ma life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell ya what, people throw away all kinds of shit, pardon ma french. There's all the usual stuff, ya know, typical garbage, food and just trash. But they also throw things they'd never want no one to know about. Toys and sexy underwear ya'd only use in the privacy of yer home, if ya know what I mean. Bibles, ya wouldn't believe the number of bibles I saw once I started payin' attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never noticed any of these things until I quit smokin'. I was constantly watchin' what I was pushin' ‘round with ma dozer. It was fascinatin'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then one day, I spotted what looked like a perfectly good iPhone sittin' on top of a pile of trash. The screen weren't broken and it was pretty clean for just bein' dumped out of the back of a truck. So I stopped ma dozer and jumped out to grab it. That's technically against the rules but there weren't no one around to run me over in their dozer or report me, so I figured why not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I grab it. Up close it still looked like it was in great shape. I wiped off whatever mess it had gotten in transport and climbed back in the cab of ma dozer and went back to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ain't nothin' but a country boy redneck, I didn't know much about fixin' phones or nothin' like that. So I YouTubed how to get it workin' again. I figured it was a long shot but I'd try to fix it up to give to ma wife, God Bless her, as a gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, long story short that phone was dead but I did come across a video talkin' about how valuable the innards of a phone are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of gold in ‘em things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I popped open that phone and took it apart. I started typin' in the numbers printed on the little components into the Google Machine and hell ya could sell a lot of those little doohickeys for cash and people'd buy up as many as ya could get yer hand on. They wanted tons of ‘em&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I was on the hunt. I grabbed up every electronic device I could find. I tried to keep ma dozer separate from the other guys so I could jump out and not be seen breakin' the rules or get run'd over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And ya wouldn't believe it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People'd spend all that money on somethin' and just toss it in the trash. That first day I took home laptops, phones, stereo equipment. Everythin' I could fit in the cab of ma dozer got picked up. I still can't believe that I hadn't see all of this stuff before&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workin' in a landfill has the benefit of work never comin' home to the family, except for the smell, occasionally. So ma wife, God Bless her, was not very happy when I showed up that evenin' with a truck full of trash. The trash was supposed to go to the dump and stay there she told me. I said I know, I know but ya won't have to seen none of this never again. I took it all out to ma back shed where I like to tinker with stuff. I got to work breakin' it all down and sortin' all the pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accordin' to the Google Machine I'd struck it rich. All the stuff I couldn't sell I'd take back and dump it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a week, I had enough to sell and off it went. And I tell ya what! I got two weeks wages off a week of searchin' and tinkerin'. I's so damn excited I grabbed up ma wife, God Bless her, and we went out to a fancy dinner date at the Red Lobsters, she really loves their coleslaw and I can't get enough of those little biscuits. She celebrated with a glass of fancy sweet wine and I had me a Budweiser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought to maself, I could really get used to this, sellin' trash and eatin' fancy dinners&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to be pretty good at findin' stuff. I's seein' it everywhere. I'd come home with more and more little devices, so much that I got ma wife, God Bless her, helpin' me. And soon enough ma kids were in the back shed breakin' things apart, sortin' little doohickeys. We had us a family business goin'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It got to the point at work, I's jumpin' out of ma dozer to snatch stuff more than I was doin' ma job. The bosses didn't like that much so I had to work out a better system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd get to work before dawn and search around with a flashlight ‘til ma shift started. Then I'd work ma regular job, occasionally jumpin' down to grab somethin' too good to pass up. Then when ma shift was over I'd search ‘til a little after dark and take ma haul home. Ma wife, God Bless her, and kids would work on breakin' everythin' down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And wouldn't ya know it! With this new system I started bringin' home even more stuff, and had to hire a high school kid to come over to the shed in the afternoons to help out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We was findin' and sellin' off mountains of gold and other fancy metals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time I was only grabbin' the small stuff that'd pack the biggest punch. I could've gathered up all the metals like warshin' machines and the like, and sold to em to recyclers but it was a lot of work to load most of it in ma truck and the payoff was less&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I'd get to tired breakin' things down, I'd go to the Google Machine some more and try findin' other ways to make a buck off the gold mine I went to every day. In ma searches I came across a lady who's wantin' to buy up old landfills, dig up all the trash to run through this incinerator contraption and resell the land that used to be a dump for new development. She's already a Gazillionaire at the time and was gettin' close to startin' a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought to maself, I know how to bury trash, I'm sure I could dig it up too, and I could find all the recyclin' to sell. Maybe I could turn this into a thing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I told ma wife, God Bless her, all about ma plan and how'd it be a risk and what all I'd have to do to get started and she said “OK! Let's do it!” I did promise her more fancy dinners at the Longhorns or the Red Lobsters if it worked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sent that gazillionaire an email with ma ideas and what I'd already been doin'. And she wrote me back with an even better idea! We were off to the races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I'm just an old redneck that drives a bulldozer around so Ms. Gazillionaire took care of all the government regulations and hired the educated environmental types. There was a lot of that sort of stuff to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the rubber hit the road I was in charge and boy was that fun! I was still down in the dirt every day diggin'. I had to follow all the rules about dealin' with Methane such and such, but we was really gettin' after it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That first dump took us 5 years, and we learned a lot. Ms. Gazillionaire made boohoos of money, but so did me and ma crew I'd put together. I weren't quite the gazillionaire as she was but I sure as hell weren't hurtin'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She asked me if I'd do more projects with her and I said “Shoot yeah I will” and here we are twenty some odd years later and I'm tellin' ma story to the President of the United States. We've now done somethin' like 70 landfills but ya already know that. I think that's probably why ya brought us here to have dinner with ya and that fancy environmental award ya gave us. But I've rambled on for too long now. Ma wife, God bless her, she says I just ramble and ramble sometimes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and one more thing, bein' the first ever landfill miner weren't a glamorous job, but it did get us a fancy dinner at the White House…. and, I did promise fancy dinners for ma wife, God Bless her.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Shaw Gravitt</name><email>smgravitt@gmail.com</email></author><summary>There is a shit ton, pardon ma french, of money to be made as a landfill miner, but I ‘spect ya already know that.
I started out as a heavy equipment operator, ma job was to make sure all the garbage dumped was packed down good'n'tight and then bury it.
It was a good job.
For the first 5 or 6 years I kept ma mind occupied by smokin' cigarettes. I'd just smoke one after the other and push the trash around, bury it, keep the dump goin'. It was good honest work, ya got over the smell eventually and we got insurance outta it.
But anyway, I'd drive ma dozer around and smoke like a chimney all day ‘til ma wife, God Bless her, told me I had to quit. I told her smokin' weren't any worse than the trash air I was breathin' all day long.
She weren't havin' none of it
I had to quit smokin'. So I did. It weren't easy and it took me a good while, I mean hell, what was I supposed to do all day with ma wanderin' mind, sittin' in the cab of ma dozer all by maself.
Ya know what helped me quit?
That damn first iPhone I found. That thing changed ma life.
I tell ya what, people throw away all kinds of shit, pardon ma french. There's all the usual stuff, ya know, typical garbage, food and just trash. But they also throw things they'd never want no one to know about. Toys and sexy underwear ya'd only use in the privacy of yer home, if ya know what I mean. Bibles, ya wouldn't believe the number of bibles I saw once I started payin' attention.
I never noticed any of these things until I quit smokin'. I was constantly watchin' what I was pushin' ‘round with ma dozer. It was fascinatin'.
Then one day, I spotted what looked like a perfectly good iPhone sittin' on top of a pile of trash. The screen weren't broken and it was pretty clean for just bein' dumped out of the back of a truck. So I stopped ma dozer and jumped out to grab it. That's technically against the rules but there weren't no one around to run me over in their dozer or report me, so I figured why not.
So I grab it. Up close it still looked like it was in great shape. I wiped off whatever mess it had gotten in transport and climbed back in the cab of ma dozer and went back to work.
I ain't nothin' but a country boy redneck, I didn't know much about fixin' phones or nothin' like that. So I YouTubed how to get it workin' again. I figured it was a long shot but I'd try to fix it up to give to ma wife, God Bless her, as a gift.
Well, long story short that phone was dead but I did come across a video talkin' about how valuable the innards of a phone are.
There's a lot of gold in ‘em things!
So, I popped open that phone and took it apart. I started typin' in the numbers printed on the little components into the Google Machine and hell ya could sell a lot of those little doohickeys for cash and people'd buy up as many as ya could get yer hand on. They wanted tons of ‘em
The next day I was on the hunt. I grabbed up every electronic device I could find. I tried to keep ma dozer separate from the other guys so I could jump out and not be seen breakin' the rules or get run'd over.
And ya wouldn't believe it!
People'd spend all that money on somethin' and just toss it in the trash. That first day I took home laptops, phones, stereo equipment. Everythin' I could fit in the cab of ma dozer got picked up. I still can't believe that I hadn't see all of this stuff before
Workin' in a landfill has the benefit of work never comin' home to the family, except for the smell, occasionally. So ma wife, God Bless her, was not very happy when I showed up that evenin' with a truck full of trash. The trash was supposed to go to the dump and stay there she told me. I said I know, I know but ya won't have to seen none of this never again. I took it all out to ma back shed where I like to tinker with stuff. I got to work breakin' it all down and sortin' all the pieces.
Accordin' to the Google Machine I'd struck it rich. All the stuff I couldn't sell I'd take back and dump it.
After a week, I had enough to sell and off it went. And I tell ya what! I got two weeks wages off a week of searchin' and tinkerin'. I's so damn excited I grabbed up ma wife, God Bless her, and we went out to a fancy dinner date at the Red Lobsters, she really loves their coleslaw and I can't get enough of those little biscuits. She celebrated with a glass of fancy sweet wine and I had me a Budweiser.
I thought to maself, I could really get used to this, sellin' trash and eatin' fancy dinners
I got to be pretty good at findin' stuff. I's seein' it everywhere. I'd come home with more and more little devices, so much that I got ma wife, God Bless her, helpin' me. And soon enough ma kids were in the back shed breakin' things apart, sortin' little doohickeys. We had us a family business goin'
It got to the point at work, I's jumpin' out of ma dozer to snatch stuff more than I was doin' ma job. The bosses didn't like that much so I had to work out a better system
I'd get to work before dawn and search around with a flashlight ‘til ma shift started. Then I'd work ma regular job, occasionally jumpin' down to grab somethin' too good to pass up. Then when ma shift was over I'd search ‘til a little after dark and take ma haul home. Ma wife, God Bless her, and kids would work on breakin' everythin' down.
And wouldn't ya know it! With this new system I started bringin' home even more stuff, and had to hire a high school kid to come over to the shed in the afternoons to help out
We was findin' and sellin' off mountains of gold and other fancy metals.
At the time I was only grabbin' the small stuff that'd pack the biggest punch. I could've gathered up all the metals like warshin' machines and the like, and sold to em to recyclers but it was a lot of work to load most of it in ma truck and the payoff was less
When I'd get to tired breakin' things down, I'd go to the Google Machine some more and try findin' other ways to make a buck off the gold mine I went to every day. In ma searches I came across a lady who's wantin' to buy up old landfills, dig up all the trash to run through this incinerator contraption and resell the land that used to be a dump for new development. She's already a Gazillionaire at the time and was gettin' close to startin' a project.
I thought to maself, I know how to bury trash, I'm sure I could dig it up too, and I could find all the recyclin' to sell. Maybe I could turn this into a thing
So I told ma wife, God Bless her, all about ma plan and how'd it be a risk and what all I'd have to do to get started and she said “OK! Let's do it!” I did promise her more fancy dinners at the Longhorns or the Red Lobsters if it worked out.
I sent that gazillionaire an email with ma ideas and what I'd already been doin'. And she wrote me back with an even better idea! We were off to the races.
Now I'm just an old redneck that drives a bulldozer around so Ms. Gazillionaire took care of all the government regulations and hired the educated environmental types. There was a lot of that sort of stuff to be done.
When the rubber hit the road I was in charge and boy was that fun! I was still down in the dirt every day diggin'. I had to follow all the rules about dealin' with Methane such and such, but we was really gettin' after it.
That first dump took us 5 years, and we learned a lot. Ms. Gazillionaire made boohoos of money, but so did me and ma crew I'd put together. I weren't quite the gazillionaire as she was but I sure as hell weren't hurtin'
She asked me if I'd do more projects with her and I said “Shoot yeah I will” and here we are twenty some odd years later and I'm tellin' ma story to the President of the United States. We've now done somethin' like 70 landfills but ya already know that. I think that's probably why ya brought us here to have dinner with ya and that fancy environmental award ya gave us. But I've rambled on for too long now. Ma wife, God bless her, she says I just ramble and ramble sometimes
Oh and one more thing, bein' the first ever landfill miner weren't a glamorous job, but it did get us a fancy dinner at the White House…. and, I did promise fancy dinners for ma wife, God Bless her.</summary></entry></feed>
